<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rails | Thomas' Dev Mind]]></title>
  <link href="http://thomas.holmes.io/blog/categories/rails/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thomas.holmes.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-09T23:03:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://thomas.holmes.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Holmes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby, Rails, And Friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomas.holmes.io/posts/ruby-rails-and-friends/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomas.holmes.io/posts/ruby-rails-and-friends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last 6 months I’ve been slowly teaching myself Ruby on Rails. It’s been a lot of fun and I’ve loved most every minute of it. My last run at web development was several years ago before technologies like Heroku were common. I spent some time trying to learn Django but did not find the ecosystem quite as mature as I would have liked. I found myself stuck playing sysadmin on a webserver, which is a role I am neither interested in or great at. So I hung up web development, experimented with mobile went back to desktop application development.</p>

<p>Four years later, enter Ruby on Rails. I’m having a blast. The tools are great. The community is wonderful. And after spending every day for two years with my nose buried in Visual Studio I am thrilled to be back to vim. It is <em>bliss</em>.</p>

<p>I’m active on GitHub and attend several regular meetings and extra events with the Ruby community. I’ve made tons of new friends and enjoying all of it. I’ve hardly played a video game in months and I can hardly believe it. I’ve got motivation to work a full day and then another three or four every night. It’s all fun.</p>

<p>If you feel like you’re missing something in your life as a developer try to find a local group. It has made all of the difference.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
